Tristan Alexander

Plant Operating Technician/Board Operator - Air Products Inc

Chicago, IL 60619 alexandertristan1022@yahoo.com 773-441-8396

High capacity professional with 10yrs of hand -on experience in production, quality -assurance, work-detail, facility managing & maintenance in a diverse industrial environment. Confident team leadership in training & supervising multi - functional groups to provide equipment repair & maintenance and site safety.

Willing to relocate to: South Bend, IN - Rockford, IL - south Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Plant Operating Technician/Board Operator

Air Products Inc March 2015 to June 2018

Control Room Operator, Responsible for chemical operations in a SO2 plant while monitoring plant using DC's computer controls and video technology. Conveying info to field operator for troubleshooting and routine maintenance while performing in compliance with EPA and Government standards.

- Proficient in preventative maintenance of boilers, blowers, centrifuges, displacement pumps, agitators, tanks, vacuum pumps, and various chemical process equipment and acids
- Read and interpret P&ID's, prepare/plan work permits
- Experience with basic electrical systems and high voltage (4160w), Tie Breaker/Switchgear operating procedures
- Conveyers and air cylinders, sensors, and motor speed
- PLC (industrial maintenance, computer control systems)
- Pumps troubleshooting, seals/motor replacement.
- Pneumatics /air compression (e.g. valves, motor brakes, cylinders, solenoids)
- Schematics and electrical blueprints with switches, starter.
- Effective use of Forklift/high-lo, Dump Truck, Kubota tractors experience
- Preventive Maintenance (PM's) computerized preventative charts and data.

Maintenance Manager

Montgomery Place Retirement Living Facility 2011 to 2015

- Oversee the hiring and training new personnel.
- Responsible for scheduling and the supervision of 15 direct reporting personnel.
- Clearly define job responsibilities and the company's mission to new hires as outlined by the organization's ever-changing business needs.
- Maintained flexibility within a \$750,000 maintenance budget, achieving a \$16,000 saving in second quarter through vendor changes, expense control, and proposal development and other necessary modifications.

- Manage facilities operation for 211 rental units and the common grounds for the facility.
- Successfully reconstructed the installation of updated HVAC and Security Systems.
- Maintaining a proficient rating in as it relates to fire, safety and health inspection compliance.
- Improved existing preventative maintenance program while ensuring the safety of all residents and staff through continuous testing of fire alarms, boiler and generator systems

Building Maintenance

Chicago Public Schools 2007 to 2011

- Maintained and operated large and small scale hvac, electrical, plumbing, boiler and support systems Efficiently completed work orders and conducting preventative maintenance on hvac and boiler systems.
- Responsible for troubleshooting and validating repairs in a timely manner.
- Managed maintenance department inventory, scheduling and the custodial personnel of 5.

Education

Certification in Universal HVAC

Environmental Technical Inst - Blue Island, IL 2008

Joliet Junior College - Joliet, IL 2004

Skills

Adapatability & flexibility, decision making, Leadership & Management, self-motivation, Communication

Certifications/Licenses

HVAC